Once again, in this clip, we are going to be hooping in the opposite direction, a very challenging thing to do.
Make sure that you give yourself some extra good energy when trying this.
I hoop to the left, so now I'm going to try it to the right.
Spin the hoop to the left and off to the right.
Here we go.
When Hannah was doing it, one foot was in front of the other, kind of rocking back and forth.
That's a great way to get the momentum of the hoop going, but now we want to make it look a little bit cooler.
Let's take the feet hip width distance apart.
Actually, my hips aren't that wide.
A little bit further apart than hip width.
Bend your knees and start rocking slightly back and forth.
Close your eyes and really feel the hoop moving around your body.
Notice when it presses into your front right hip and into your back.
When the hoop presses against the right hip, slowly start to turn to your right.
Then you can either pivot on one foot or you can step with both feet.
Kind of back and forth.
As you can see, I'm shifting the weight from right to left.
If the hoop starts to fall, really give it a kick with that right hip to keep it going.
Once again, turning.
You can shift your weight.
Make sure you're conscious of your arms.
It's real easy to do funny things with your arms in the hoop.
As you're turning, pushing into the hoop, let's try turning in the opposite direction.
Hopefully I can do this.
It might be kind of funny.
Once again, if it starts to fall, really give it that kick.
Keep it going again.
Alright, let's try that one more time.
Hooping in the opposite.
Actually, turning in the opposite direction.
Like I said, it's going to feel like you're in a blender.
That'll be a little bit easier.
Flowing with the hoop.
It if starts to fall, give it that nice kick to keep it going.
Turning away from the hoop and turning with the hoop.
The faster you turn, the more the hoop will float.
The slower you turn, the more you can guide it with the hips.
Once again, try lifting up onto the toes.
Lifting up, lifting up, coming down.
This side is going to be a little strange.
Take your time.
Have fun with it.
Be patient with yourself.
You can do it.